Guide to the Cornell-Community Waste Management Advisory Committee records, 1996-2004.
Cornell-Community Waste Management Advisory Committee records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell-Community Waste Management Advisory Committee records, 1996-2004.
24-20-3973
Cornell-Community Waste Management Advisory Committee.
15 cubic feet.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
CCWMAC materials including environmental impact statements.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
CCWMAC (pronounced "Cowmac") was assembled in 1996 following protests from some area residents opposed to a proposed incinerator upgrade and expansion. The committee was composed of about two dozen representatives of environmental groups, government agencies, community organizations, elected officials and such campus entities as the Cornell Greens, the Cornell United Progressives, the Student, Graduate & Professional Student and University Assemblies and the Faculty Senate. Work of the committee was coordinated by the Community Dispute Resolution Center, an independent Ithaca-based non-profit organization A consensus agreement in 1998 set the direction for an innovative approach to replacing Cornell's existing incinerator with a tandem of alternative technologies. A CCWMAC subcommittee spent three months writing a final report that the committee adopted Oct. 8, when it also approved a set of recommendations for further waste minimization at Cornell. In 2010 Cornell's incinerator at the College of Veterinary Medicine was officially shut down and replaced with a new digester for disposing of animal remains.The new system is part of a Waste Management Facility project that also includes removing the incinerator and installing a steam sterilization and shredding system for disposing of the university's medical waste, which will be completed in 2010. In 2011 A new Rotoclave (rotating autoclave) at Cornell's Waste Management Facility was dedicated, promising to dispose of the university's medical wastes in a safe, environmentally friendly manner, while saving energy
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
CCWMAC materials including environmental impact statements.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell-Community Waste Management Advisory Committee.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine.
Subjects:
Animal waste management.; Veterinary hygiene.; Animal waste -- Environmental aspects -- Ithaca.; Animal waste -- Environmental aspects; Animal waste -- Management; Veterinary hygiene
Places:
New York (State) -- Ithaca
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. General Documents
Series II. CCVM
Series III. CDRC
Series IV. Consultant's Reports
Series V. Controversy and Press
Series VI. Environmental Impact Study
Series VII. Vendor Files
Series VIII. Waste Management Project Material
Series IX. Waste Minimization and Management
Series X. Working Groups
Series XI. Substantive Materials
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General Documents
  - CCWMAC additional reports (I) and photos, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - CCWMAC additional reports (II), 1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - CCWMAC additional reports (III), 1998-05 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - CCWMAC additional report copies, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - CCWMAC assorted documents (I), 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    vendor responses, waste disposal working group, correspondence, handwritten notes, substantive materials
  - CCWMAC assorted documents (II), 1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    memos, correspondence, handwritten notes, regulation information/guidelines,
  - CCWMAC correspondence, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    letter to the editor of the Cornell Chronicle; Dean Smith
  - CCWMAC final meeting minutes, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    meeting minutes, 1998 waste minimization report
  - CCWMAC: Albany meeting and follow-up, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    grievances concerning the implementation of CCMAC's recommendation and SUCF
  - CCWMAC assorted documents, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    correspondence, CDRC, CCWMAC handwritten notes, Community Advisory Committee
  - CCWMAC: EPA, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Path waste incinerator: nook for rags info; Williams/Mahr critiques; handwritten notes and correspondence
  - CCWMAC meeting documents, 1997-2001 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    minutes, CDRC, handwritten notes, SUCF correspondence, draft of letter encouraging participation in the Ithaca Democratic caucus, list of democrats in Ithaca with address and phone numbers
  - CCWMAC notes, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    meetings notes, "misc. stuff from desk"
  - CCWMAC - Plasma, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    handwriten notes, correspondence, plasma information, Plasmarc
  - CCWMAC Recommendations and Summary of Activities October 1996-July 1998, 1996-10-1998-07 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Revised drafts and comments
  - CCWMAC retreat, 1992-1998 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    certificate of non-compliance for CU incinerator, cover letter and quarterly report for SUNY HSC/Syracuse regulated medical waste incinerator.
  - CCWMAC tech selection/plans, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    criteria, vendor notes, vendor responses, correspondence with Norrie Engineering Inc.
  - CCWMAC work plan and principles/criteria, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    correspondence, CCWMAC criteria questions
  - CCWMAC Report: Recommendations and Summary of Activities, 1996-10-1998-10 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Letter from Community Dispute Resolution Center: Serving Chemung, Schuyler and Tompkin Counties
  - CCWMAC Presentation: What is Prevention?, Undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - CCWMAC Pollution Prevention and Environmental Solutions in Hospitals, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Request form - Citizen's Environemtnal Coalition
  - CCWMAC Meeting Minutes and Comments, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Consultant reports and FDA HHS
  - CCWMAC Assorted Documents, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    Correspondence, memos, assessment reports
  - CCWMAC Assorted Documents (I of II), 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Drafts of reports, correspondence, meeting minutes, articles on diseases, environmental reports
  - CCWMAC Assorted Documents (II of II), 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - DRAFT Environmental Consulting Activity: Task 4, 1998-04-06 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - DRAFT CCWMAC Recommendations and Summary of Activites (10/1996-07/1998), 1998-07-23 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Letter of Transmittal: Sterile Tech Industries, Inc., 1997-09-04 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - CCWMAC Assorted Documents, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    Correspondence, memos, NYSERDA agreement
  - CCWMAC Assorted Documents, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    HEC and Hirschhorn proposals, memos, drafts and revisions
  - CCWMAC Meeting Minutes (I of II), 1996-1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Assorted documents, undated handouts
  - CCWMAC Meeting Minutes (II of II), 1998 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Meeting correspondence
  - June 24 Meetings, 1996-06-24 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Research Proposal, 1989, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Inclusion of Report of departmental expenditures for 1988/89
  - Strategy/Enck, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Handwritten notes and calculations on computer paper, not all are dated with the year
  - Incinerator Questionnaire, 1996-09-03 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Handwritten comments
  - Lawyer - Notes, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Handwritten notes on computer paper
  - RMW Incinerators/Other, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Notes and Handouts, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Chronology on proposed regulated medical waste incinerator at CCVM; handwritten notes on scratch paper
  - SUCF Project #19121 Correspondence, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    Handwritten notes
  - Notes - Blaud Dispute, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Expenses, 1996-1999 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Research Needs, Fall 1996 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Names List/Decision-Makers, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Handwritten notes on scratch paper that date 1996; includes a newspaper clipping about health professionals needing to answer environmental challenge
  - Official Correspondence, Fall 1996, Undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Original folder with handwritten notes
  - CCMWI Assorted Documents, 1996-1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
    Correspondence, flyers, meeting notes, handwritten notes
  - Typed Notes/Notes to File, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Selected Correspondence (1/7/98), 1998 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    Original folder labeled with "1/7/98"; correspondence inside date 1996
  - Dean's Meeting (5/13/99) Langevin "Programming", 1999 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    Original folder labeled 5/13/99; correspondence inside dates 6/7/99
  - March 30, 1999 Meeting, 1999-03 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    Handwritten notes; correspondence dates 3/23/1999
  - CCMWI Notes and Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    Original folder labeled with "1/99-3/99"
  - CCMWI Memos, Fall 1998 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Assorted Documents, 1997-1999 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    Original folder labeled "Dec/3/99"; documents inside date 1997-1999; correspondence from NY State Department of Environmental Conservation; a copy of EPA guidelines
  - Connett, Waste Not, 1997-12-10,1998-01-20 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    Handwritten notes ("What I've learned")
  - CCWMAC-2 Assorted Documents (Box 9, Folder 35)
    Correspondence, handwritten notes; small newspaper clipping of article on mad cow disease
  - Dean's Meeting, 1996, undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
    Handwritten notes on scratch paper
  - Quimby Proposal, 1997-1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
    Drafts, handwritten notes; notes on meeting with Quimby, stack of index cards
  - Dispute Resolution, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    Handwritten notes; Ruth Mahr's Alternative Dispute-Resolution (with comments); one of original folders named "Everyone's Backyard: Dispute Resolution"
  - Bland's Notes, Undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Notes on telephone conversations, 1996-2000, undated (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Copies to Ruth Mahr, 1993-1997 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Correspondence on incinerator, CCMWI, SUCF
  - Strategy, 1996, 1998, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Related to CCMWI; handwritten notes; correspondence
  - Dispute Resolution (II), 1996, 1999, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Handwritten notes; drafts of alternative dispute resolution + comments; original folder named "Everyone's Backyard: Dispute Resolution"
  - Public Statements, 1996-1998, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Drafts, correspondence, newspaper article; handwritten notes; also labeled "FHIA/Public Informational Meeting"
  - Critique of FEAF, 1992-1997, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Includes documents related to Wysocki, ITH Planning Board, T/ITH Files, "etc" (written on original folder); handwritten notes
  - CCWMAC/CCMWI E-mail lists, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - SUCF Correspondence, FEAF Documents, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - CCWMAC Lib, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Malcom Pirnie - Scope of Work; environmental permit; annual report for CVM Incinerator Facility; Architect's Agreement
  - CCMWI Side Meetings, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Correspondence; memos; notes
  - Brcak File, 1992, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Memos and correspondence
  - Whistle Blowers, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Notes written on scratch paper
  - ACS Talk, Undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Gwendolyn Mills' Thesis: Re-Evaluation of Alternative Dispute Resolution, Spring 1998 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Appendices date from 1996 and 1997
  - CCWMAC, 1997-02-25; V-10467 (Box 10)
    VHS
  - CCWMAC, 1997-03-11; V-10468 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-03-25; V-10469 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-04-09; V-10470 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-05-05; V-10471 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-05-21; V-10472 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-05-27; V-10473 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-06-09; V-10474 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-06-30; V-10475 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-07-14; V-10476 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-08-26; V-10477 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape I of II, 1997-09-09; V-10478 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape II of II, 1997-09-09; V-10479 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-09-29; V-10480 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-11-13; V-10481 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-11-24; V-10482 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1997-12-09; V-10483 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape I of II, 1998-01-27; V-10484 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape II of II, 1998-01-27; V-10485 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1998-02-11; V-10486 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape I of II, 1998-03-02; V-10487 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape II of II, 1998-03-02; V-10488 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1998-03-25; V-10489 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape #1, 1998-04-14; V-10490 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape #2, 1998-04-14; V-10491 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape 1, 1998-04-20; V-10492 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape 2, 1998-04-20; V-10493 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape 1 of 3, 1998-04-24; V-10494 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape 2 of 3, 1998-04-24; V-10495 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape 3 of 3, 1998-04-25; V-10496 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape 1 of 2, 1998-05-11; V-10497 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC Tape 2 of 2, 1998-05-11; V-10498 (Box 10)
  - CCWMAC, 1998-05-26; V-10499 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC Tape 1 of 2, 1998-06-01; V-10500 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC Tape 2 of 2, 1998-06-01; V-10501 (Box 11)
  - Vendor Meeting Tape 1 of 3, 1998-06-01; V-10502 (Box 11)
  - Vendor Meeting Tape 2 of 3, 1998-06-01; V-10503 (Box 11)
  - Vendor Meeting Tape 3 of 3, 1998-06-01; V-10504 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC Tape 1 of 2, 1998-06-15; V-10505 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC Tape 2 of 2, 1998-06-15; V-10506 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC Saturday Retreat Tape 1 of 3, 1998-06-20; V-10507 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC Saturday Retreat Tape 2 of 3, 1998-06-20; V-10508 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC Saturday Retreat Tape 3 of 3, 1998-06-20; V-10509 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC, 1998-07-14; V-10510 (Box 11)
  - San-I-Pak 200/300 Sterilizer/Compactor, Undated; V-10511 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC Info Discussion w/ Ed Krisiumus, 1997-06-16; V-10512 (Box 11)
  - 4/29 VA Tech Talk, Undated; V-10513 (Box 11)
  - "Apr. 29 VA Talk", Undated; V-10514 (Box 11)
  - CLWG Meeting w/ Joel Hirschorn, 1998-01-09; V-10515 (Box 11)
  - "Are we scaring ourselves to death," ABC News Special, 1996-09-09; V-10516 (Box 11)
  - Partial Tape, undated, Undated; V-10517 (Box 11)
  - Nova: The Brain Eater WG 2505, Undated; V-10518 (Box 11)
  - Hollie Shaner's Speech, Undated; V-10519 (Box 11)
  - Vendor Visits, 1997-07; V-10520 (Box 11)
  - Consumat Environmental Sys (Jerry Holcomb), 1997-08-26; V-10521 (Box 11)
  - Norrie Engineering, 1997-08-27; V-10522 (Box 11)
  - Hydroclave Environmental Systems, 1997-08-14; V-10523 (Box 11)
  - No Time to Waste: Resource Conservation for Hospitals, Undated; V-10524 (Box 11)
    Date may be on actual tape
  - Expert Solutions for Managing Health Care Waste (San-I-Pak), 1996-08-14; V-10525 (Box 11)
  - Walsh Waste Tracker System Disk 1, Undated; FD-672 (Box 11)
    Enclosed in original envelope
    Floppy Disk
  - Walsh Waste Tracker System Disk 2, Undated; FD-673 (Box 11)
  - Show Demo: The Waste Tracker, Undated; FD-674 (Box 11)
    In smaller box
  - Email about: PAR, CLWG minutes, Undated; FD-675 (Box 11)
  - Emails about: CLWG, Waste Min, options, CCWMAC Ann., Undated; FD-676 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC Report; Email about: CCWG, Undated; FD-677 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC files about: Minimization, Options, PAR, Undated; FD-678 (Box 11)
  - Word files about: CLWG, Library, Matrix, Undated; FD-679 (Box 11)
  - Word files about: CCWG, Criteria, Funding, Guertin, Undated; FD-680 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC files prior to September 1997, Undated; FD-681 (Box 11)
  - Cornell - Hirschhorn Reports, Undated; FD-682 (Box 11)
  - CCWMAC Stuff, 1998-07-20; FD-683 (Box 11)
    Original envelope labeled "Computer Disk of final CCWMAC documents"
  - Meeting of 10/7/97, 1997-10-07; tr-16732 (Box 11)
    Cassette
  - Part I + II, 1997-09-18; tr-16733 (Box 11)
    Had a post-it that said "Try these out - Linda"
  - Audio tape, Undated; tr-16734 (Box 11)
- Series II. CCVM
  - Alkaline Hydrolysis test plan and results: CCVM, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    correspondence, conflict resolution
  - CCVM draft tech memo and response, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - CCVM: EPA regulations and comments, 2000-01 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    comments on proposed
  - CCVM: implementation process, 2000-2005 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    urgent 2005 call to action by Ruth Mahr et al; project design, meeting agendas
  - CCVM - Q and A regarding WMF, 1999-07 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    responses to questions raised by community members and regulatory officials regarding project definition document dated May 10, 1999; correspondence
  - CCVM Waste Management, 2000-2002 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Preliminary Malcom Pirnie report (Screening of Waste Treatment Technologies Waste Stream Management Facility) April 2000; meeting notes; notice of intent of Malcom Pirnie to prepare supplemental EIS; Opinion and Report on High Pressure Alkaline Hydrolysis by European Commission
  - CCVM 2000-2001, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    CCVM meeting 1/29/01 documents; public information session powerpoint; waste management quarterly update meeting; draft scope for EIS; correspondence; preliminary report on Alkaline hydrolyzate anaerobic digestion feasibility study; majority of correspondence addressed to Ruth Mahr
  - CCVM Animal and Medical Waste Treatment Study and Energy Evaluation - Report 2, 1998-08-18 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Additional post-its
  - CCVM Animal and Medical Waste Treatment Study and Energy Evaluation - Report 1, 1998-05-11 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Series III. CDRC
  - CCWMAC (Incinerator Project) reports, 1996-10-1998-10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Cornell College of Veterinary Medicine Wate Minimization and Pollution Prevention Report August 1997; A Focused Waste Minimization and Pollution Control Assessment for the Cornell College of Veterinary Medicine June 22, 1998; Final Report of the Cornell-Community Waste Management Advisory Committee (CCWMAC): Recommendations and summary of activities October 1996-October 1998; table of contents, log of users of series materials
  - CCWMAC minutes, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Community Dispute Resolution Center (CDRC) meeting proceedings/minutes, relevant correspondence, supporting materials intended to brief meeting participants
  - CCWMAC raw notes (CDRC minutes), 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    raw CDRC minutes
  - CDRC: Process Issues, 1997-10 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Notes for telephone conversation with Judy Saul
- Series IV. Consultant's Reports
  - Hirschhorn references, 1986-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    waste management information
  - Hirschhorn reports, 1998-02-06-1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Malcom Pirnie, 2002-05 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    correspondence, Final Environmental Impact Statement Cornell College of Veterinary Medicine Waste Management Facility
  - Statements of qualifications from consultants, 1997-08-1997-09 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - STV and HEC qualifications, 1997-03-1997-10 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - supplemental work from Hirschhorn, 1982-01-1998-03 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    materials used for task 4 report and not received from Cornell: STI data package on VOC emissions, Midwest Research Inst. April 1996 report for EPA, Hydroclave patent information package, San-I-Pak package, Medwaste Tech. Package, correspondence, reports, memos
  - consultant scope of work, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Hh contract amendment, Hirschhorn scope of work, HEC proposal, additional notes
  - general consultants: STV/HEC notes, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    handwritten notes; scope of work (1998)
  - Guertin/HEC Reports comments, 1998-05 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - HEC consultant proposal, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - HEC/Guertin Report I, 1998-01-1998-04 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    report, correspondence
  - HEC Report II - Final, 1998-07-07 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    HEC/Guertin
  - HEC Report II - revisions and comments, 1998-06 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    revisions, responses, Guertin's responses to comments
  - Hirschhorn Report I, 1998-01-1998-02 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Hirschhorn Report II, 1998-01-1998-04 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Hirschhorn III/Final Report, 1998-03-1998-06 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    Hirschhorn: Final Report III and other assorted/miscellaneous Hirschhorn documents (notes, correspondence,
  - STV incorporated: vendor qualifications, 1993-1997 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    statement of qualifications, examples of past work, correspondence
  - Hirschhorn/HEC/Guertin/Norrie Engineering Reports and Drafts, 1997-1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Lists of criteria
  - Rump Org. - Consultant, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Correspondence; questions about incinerator
  - Doucet and Mainka, 1994-1997, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Note on front of folder
- Series V. Controversy and Press
  - Newspaper clipppings and memos, 1996 -1997 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Vet waste management controversey 1996, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    newspaper clippings, fliers, handwritten notes, correspondence
  - Vet waste management controversey 1998, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Email correspondence regarding controversey, op-eds, notes, memos, reports
  - Woodard Talk, 1997-04 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Handouts with handwritten notes on reverse
  - 1996 Incinerator press, 1996-2000 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    newspaper clippings, correspondence, newsletters, handouts, notes
  - Incinerator - Ithaca Times, 2002-04-17 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Correspondence, 1990-1997, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Flyers on how to oppose incinerator proposal
  - Press Release: Citizens Concerned about Incineration, 1996-08-02 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Unsent draft
  - Letters/Editors, 1999-05 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    Original folder was labeled May 99 but there's a copy of an opinion article that dates April 1999; there was a large stack of duplicates of "Incinerator Alert!" flyer
  - Newspaper and Press Releases, 1996-1999, undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
    A few undated articles and handwritten notes
- Series VI. Environmental Impact Study
  - CVM Waste Management Facility Final Environmental Impact Study, 2002-05 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - DEIS comments, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Study Volume I of III, 2002-02 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Study Volume II of III, 2002-02 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Study Volume III of III, 2002-02 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Final Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement, 2004-04 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Cornell College of Veterinary Medicine Waste Management Facility
  - Part 360 Quarterly and Annual Reports, 2000-01-28-2005-07-28 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Cornell CVM Incinerator Facility reports
  - Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement, 2003-12 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 6NYCRR Part 360 Permit, 1999-10-05 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement: SUCF Project No. 19142, 2003-12-18 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Final Environmental Impact Statement, 2002-05 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Letter of submission of FEIS from Malcolm Pirnie; notice of completion of FEIS
  - DRAFT Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement, 2003-11 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Memorandum
  - EPA Report: Medical Waste Incinerators - Background Info, 1994-07 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Extra page of effects of combustion controls; handwritten abstract
  - CVM DRAFT Environmental Impact Statement Volume I of II, 2002-02 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Letter of submission from Malcom Pirnie
  - Impact Analysis/Ruth, Undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Environment Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    Correspondence; handwritten notes
  - Incinerator Questions, Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Index cards; written on scratch paper
  - DEIS for Proposed CCVM Waste Management Facility, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Series VII. Vendor Files
  - vendor files table of contents, 1998-03-11 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - CCWMAC correspondence to vendors, 1997-02-14-1998-02-03 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    requests for information, letters regarding effects of chemicals of their treatment process
  - Hydroclave, 1997-05-23-1998-06-16 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    correspondence, presentation, notes
  - Medical SafeTEC/Circle Medical Products, 1993-1998-03-23 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    information about an infectious waste processing system